Millions of years ago...
a meteorite made of vibranium...
the strongest substance
in the universe...
struck the continent of Africa...
affecting the plant life around it.
And when the time of men came...
five tribes settled on
it and called it...
Wakanda.
The tribes lived in constant
war with each other
until a warrior shaman
received a vision from
the panther goddess Bast
who led him to the
heart-shaped herb.
A plant that granted him
superhuman strength,
speed and instincts.
The warrior became king...
and the first Black Panther.
The protector of Wakanda.
Four tribes agreed to live
under the king's rule.
But the Jabari Tribe isolated
themselves in the mountains.
The Wakandans used vibranium
to develop technology
more advanced than
any other nation.
But as Wakanda thrived,
the world around it
descended further into chaos.
To keep vibranium safe,
the Wakandans vowed
to hide in plain sight...
keeping the truth of their
power from the outside world.
-Lucky shot!
-That ain't lucky!
-Whatever!
-Get outta here!
Check up. No dirties.
What?
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Got you, E!
Watch me get this...
Tim Hardaway style. That's
what I call it, baby.
Hey, look, if we get in and out
quick, won't be no worries.
You're in the van, come
in through from the west.
Come around the corner.
-Land right here.
-Mm-hmm.
Me and the twins
pullin' up right here.
We're leaving this car behind, okay?
We come this...
Hide the straps.
Yo, is it the feds?
No.
These two Grace Jones
lookin' chicks.
They own spears.
Open it.
You serious?
They won't knock again.
Who are you?
Prince N'Jobu, son of Azzuri.
Show me you're one of us.
My King.
Leave us.
This is James. I trust him
with my life. He stays.
With your permission,
King T'Chaka.
As you wish.
At ease.
Come, brother.
Let me see how you're
holding up.
You look strong.
Glory to Bast,
I am in good health.
How's home?
Not so good.
Little brother.
There has been an attack.
This man...
Ulysses Klaue...
stole a quarter ton
of vibranium from us
and triggered a bomb at
the border to escape.
Many lives were lost.
He knew where we hid
the vibranium...
and how to strike.
He had someone on the inside.
Why are you here?
Because I want you to
look me in the eyes...
and tell me why
you betrayed Wakanda.
I did no such thing.
Tell him who you are.
Zuri, son of Badu.
What?
James.
James, you lied to me?
-Leave him be.
-I let you into my home...
You were Wakandan
this whole time?
-You betrayed Wakanda!
-How can you lie to me?
Stand!
Down.
Did you think that you were
the only spy we sent here?
Prince N'Jobu,
you will return home at once...
where you will face the Council
and inform them of your crimes.
Look up!
Guard your man, guard your man!
The tiny nation of Wakanda
is mourning the death
of its monarch, King T'Chaka.
The beloved ruler was one
of many confirmed dead
after a terrorist attack at the
United Nations a week ago.
The suspect has since
been apprehended.
Though it remains one of the
poorest countries in the world,
fortified by mountain ranges
and an impenetrable rain forest,
Wakanda does not engage
in international trade
or accept aid.
The succession of the throne
is expected to fall to the oldest
of the king's two children,
Prince T'Challa.
My prince...
Coming up on them now.
Sambisa Forest, Nigeria
No need, Okoye. I can
handle this alone.
Hmm.
I will get Nakia out
as quickly as possible.
Just don't freeze
when you see her.
What are you talking about?
I never freeze.
What's going on?
Lost power.
Won't start.
The car not start.
What happened?
The engine's failed.
Ours too.
What is it, Captain?
Defense positions.
Are we under attack?
N'jou! Get around to the side.
Defense positions.
Hey! Defense positions!
No games.
What do you see?
Come in. Come in.
-Over there!
-Look back!
Watch out!
T'Challa, no!
This one's just a boy.
He got kidnapped as well.
Nakia...
I...
-I wanted...
-Hey!
I have her! Don't move!
I will shoot!
I will shoot her right--
You froze.
Ah.
Why are you here?
You ruined my mission.
My father is dead, Nakia.
I will be crowned king tomorrow.
And I wish for you
to be there.
Carry yourselves home now.
And take the boy.
Get him to his people.
Thank you.
You will speak
nothing of this day.
Yes.
Thank you.
Sister Nakia...
my Prince...
we are in home.
This never gets old.
Queen Mother...
Princess...
A comfort for your loss.
Thank you, Nakia.
It is so good to have
you back with us.
Take her to the River Province
to prepare her for the ceremony.
Yes, General.
Did he freeze?
Like an antelope in headlights.
You finished?
So surprised my little
sister came to see me off
before our big day.
You wish.
I'm here for the EMP beads.
I've developed an update.
Update? No. It worked perfectly.
How many times do
I have to teach you?
Just because something works
doesn't mean that
it cannot be improved.
You are teaching me?
What do you know?
More than you.
I can't wait to see what
kind of update you make
to your ceremonial outfit.
Shuri!
Sorry, Mother!
How are you feeling today,
Mother?
Proud.
Your father and I would talk
about this day all the time.
He is with us...
and it is your time to be king.
London, United Kingdom
Good Morning.
How can I help you?
Oh, just checking out
these artifacts.
They tell me you're the expert.
Ah, you  could say that.
They're beautiful.
Where is this one from?
The Bobo Ashanti tribe.
Present day Ghana,
nineteenth century.
For real?
And what about this one?
That one's from the
Edo people of Benin,
sixteenth century.
Now, tell me about this one.
Also from Benin, seventh century.
Fula tribe, I believe.
Nah.
I beg your pardon?
It was taken by British
soldiers in Benin,
but it's from Wakanda.
And it's made out of vibranium.
Don't trip. I'ma take it
off your hands for you.
These items aren't for sale.
How do you think your
ancestors got these?
You think they
paid a fair price?
Or did they take it, like
they took everything else?
Sir, I'm going to have to...
ask you to leave.
You got all this security in here
watching me ever since I walked in.
But you ain't checking for
what you put in your body.
All right, mate, let's have it
Come on, mate, time.
I think she might not
be feeling too good.
Hey! Somebody get some help!
Come here!
Call the doctor, please!
Hey, please, somebody come help!
Medical emergency
right away in the
West African exhibit,
please, right away.
Watch out.
Step back, please. Step back.
Ho! Medics coming.
I'm gonna take a break.
Let's give the lady
some space, please.
Step back, please, gents.
Step back, please.
Hey, come here.
Come here, come here.
It's okay.
You can go, but just don't
tell anyone, all right?
Bro, why you ain't just
shoot him right here?
Because it's better to leave the
crime scene more spread out.
Makes it look like amateurs.
Now then, let's see if you know
what you're talking about.
That's just a taste.
-You're gonna be rich, boy.
-You better sell that quick.
It's already sold.
Whatever you try, the Wakandans
will probably show up.
Well, that'll make my day.
I can kill two birds
with one stone.
You're not telling me
that's vibranium too?
Nah, I'm just feelin' it.
Ahead!
I, Zuri,
son of Badu...
give to you...
Prince T'Challa...
The Black Panther!
The Prince...
will now have the strength
of the Black Panther
stripped away.
Glory to the ancestors.
Victory in ritual combat...
comes by yield or death.
If any tribe wishes to
put forth a warrior,
I now offer...
a path to the throne.
The Merchant Tribe will
not challenge today.
The Border Tribe will
The River Tribe will
not challenge today.
The Mining Tribe will
Is there any member
of a royal blood...
who wishes to challenge
for the throne?
This corset is really
uncomfortable.
So, could we all just
wrap it up and go home?
Mother!
Hey.
-Are they Jabari?
-Yes.
M'Baku, what are you doing here?
It's challenge day.
We have watched...
and listened from the mountains!
We have watched with disgust,
as your technological
advancements
have been overseen by a child!
Who scoffs at tradition!
And now you want to hand the
nation over to this prince...
who could not keep
his own father safe.
Hmm?
We will not have it.
I say, we will not have it!
I, M'Baku...
leader of the Jabari...
I accept your challenge, M'Baku.
Glory to Hanuman.
Jabari!
Dora Milaje!
Ahead!
Let the challenge begin!
Oh!
Stand up!
Come!
T'Challa!
Where is your god now?
Hey!
Yes!
No powers!
No claws!
No special suit!
Just a boy, not fit to lead!
Show him who you are!
I am Prince T'Challa!
Son of King T'Chaka!
You can do this, T'Challa!
Yes!
Come on!
Yield! Don't make me kill you!
I would rather die!
T'Challa!
You have fought with honor!
Now yield!
Your people need you.
T'Challa!
Yield, man!
Yes!
He-he-hey!
I now present to you,
King T'Challa!
The Black Panther.
Zuri.
My King.
Wakanda forever!
Allow the heart-shaped herb
to restore the powers
of the Black Panther...
and take the Ancestral Plane.
T'Chaka...
we call on you.
Come here to your son.
Glory to the ancestors.
Father.
My son.
I am sorry.
Stand up.
You are a king.
What's wrong, son?
I am not ready.
Have you not prepared...
your whole life to be king?
Have you not trained
and studied...
always by my side?
That is not what
I am talking about.
I am not ready to be without you.
A man who has not prepared
his children for his own death
has failed as a father.
Have I ever failed you?
Never.
Tell me how to best
protect Wakanda.
I want to be a great king, Baba.
Just like you.
You're going to struggle.
So you'll need to surround
yourself with people you trust.
You're a good man
with a good heart.
And it's hard for a good man
to be king.
Breathe.
T'Challa, breathe.
He was there.
My father.
Just one.
Come home, Nakia.
I'm right here.
Stay.
I came to support you
and to honor your father.
But I can't stay.
It's just, I found my
calling out there.
I've seen too many in need
just to turn a blind eye.
I can't be happy here
knowing that there's people
out there who have nothing.
What would you have
Wakanda do about it?
Share what we have.
We could provide aid
and access to technology
and refuge to those who need it.
Other countries do it,
we could it do better.
We are not alike,
these countries, Nakia.
If the world found out
what we truly are...
what we possess,
we could lose our way of life.
Wakanda is strong
enough to help others
and protect ourselves
at the same time.
If you were not so stubborn,
you would make a great queen.
I would make a great queen
because I am so stubborn.
-Ah, see, you admit it!
-If...if that's what I wanted.
Is that him?
Hoo!
Glory to Bast, man.
Is he still growing?
Of course.
I see Nakia is back.
You guys going to work it out?
T'Challa...
What's wrong?
Nakia thinks we
should be doing more.
More like what?
Foreign aid, refugee programs.
You let the refugees in,
they bring their
problems with them.
And then Wakanda is
like everywhere else.
Now if you said you
wanted me and my men...
to go out there and clean out
the world, then I'll be all for it.
But waging war on other countries
has never been our way.
You too, huh?
Bast! We're in trouble.
My King.
My love.
You will never guess who
just popped up on our radar.
A misidentified Wakandan artifact
was stolen yesterday
from a British museum.
We have learned Ulysses Klaue
plans to sell the vibranium
to an American buyer
in South Korea
tomorrow night.
Klaue has escaped our
pursuits for almost 30 years.
Not capturing him is perhaps
my father's greatest regret.
I wish to bring Klaue
back here to stand trial.
Wakanda does not need
a warrior right now.
We need a king.
My parents were killed
when he attacked.
Not a day goes by when
I do not think about
what Klaue took from us.
From me.
It's too great an
opportunity to pass.
Take me with you.
We'll take him down
together side by side.
I need you here
protecting the border.
Then I ask...
do you kill him
where he stands...
or you bring him back to us?
You have my word.
I will bring him back.
We will proceed with the mission.
My King!
Stop it. Stop it.
I've already sent a car
ahead to Busan for you.
Who are you taking
with you to Korea?
Okoye.
And Nakia as well.
You sure it's a good idea to
take your ex on a mission?
Yes.
We'll be fine. Besides, you'll be
on call should we need backup.
Yes!
I have great things
to show you, brother.
Here are your communication
devices for Korea.
Unlimited range, also equipped
with audio surveillance system.
Check these out.
Remote access Kimoyo beads.
Updated to interface directly
with my sand table.
Ah.
And what are these?
The real question is
what are those?!
Why do you have your
toes out in my lab?
What? You don't like
my royal sandals?
I wanted to go old school
for my first day.
Yeah, I bet the elders loved it.
Try them on.
Fully automated.
Like the old American
movie Baba used to watch.
Mmm.
And I made them completely
sound absorbent.
Interesting.
Guess what I call them.
Sneakers.
Because you...
Never mind.
If you're going to
take on Klaue,
you'll need the best
the design group has to offer.
Exhibit A.
-My design.
-Old tech.
-Old?
-Functional, but old.
"Hey, people are shooting me.
Wait, let me put on my helmet."
Enough.
Now, look at these.
Do you like that one?
Tempting.
But the idea is
to not be noticed.
This one.
Now tell it to go on.
Whoo!
The entire suit sits within
the teeth of the necklace.
Strike it.
-Anywhere?
-Mm-hmm.
Not that hard, genius!
You told me to strike it.
You didn't say how hard.
I invite you to my lab, and
you just kick things around?
Well, maybe you should
make it a little stronger.
Hey...
Wait a minute.
The nanites absorb
the kinetic energy
and hold it in place
for redistribution.
Very nice.
Strike it again
in the same spot.
You're recording?
For research purposes.
Delete that footage.
Busan, South Korea
This way.
Bast willing, this will go quickly
and I can get this ridiculous
thing off my head.
It looks nice. Just
whip it back and forth.
What? It's a disgrace.
Hello, Sophia.
Nice to see you.
Who are those two?
My friends from Kenya.
Very wealthy. They're good.
Good for causing trouble...
like you?
Thank you.
Spread out.
The buyer is likely
already here.
♪ You know I'll ride again ♪
♪ It's all the same ♪
♪ Tell me who's gon'
save me from myself ♪
♪ When this life is all I know ♪
The woman outside.
What "trouble" was
she referring to?
Ah. I got into a disagreement
with some ivory traders.
-Made a bit of a mess.
-Hm.
And will there be any trouble
tonight, Miss Kenyan Heiress?
It depends...
on how quickly
we finish the mission.
Can we please focus?
Thank you.
Here.
Glass of whiskey.
Eyes up.
Americans.
I count three.
Five.
How could you miss Grease
Lightning there behind you?
Six.
I just spotted an old friend
who works for the CIA.
It just got a little
more complicated.
Agent Ross.
Your Highness.
You are buying from Klaue?
What I'm doing or not doing
on behalf of the U.S. government
is none of your concern.
Now, whatever the hell
you're up to...
Do me a favor,
stay out of my way.
I gave you Zemo.
Didn't I keep it under wraps?
That the king of the
third world country
runs around in a
bulletproof cat suit?
I'd say we were even.
You really need to leave, now.
Klaue is leaving
out that door with me.
You've been warned.
Three, craps.
Hey, you won!
You know what?
I think I'll just take these,
bring 'em over here
-and hold on for safekeeping.
-Mm-hmm.
Okay, heads up.
The King of Wakanda is here.
He cannot leave with Klaue.
All right.
Vibranium from the attack on
Sokovia links back to a person
that I'm not actually saying
I'm here to make a deal with.
But that deal will
not be called off.
When the dust settles,
you and me can work
something out.
I'm not here to make a deal.
Klaue, plus eight.
General.
In position to secure our exit.
And the vibranium?
I don't see it yet.
I thought there were no
weapons allowed in here.
There's not supposed to be.
Somebody did not get the memo.
Definitely armed.
Well, that is quite the entourage.
You got a mix tape coming out?
Uh, yeah, yeah,
actually, there is one.
I'll send you the SoundCloud
link, if you like.
Hey, Dave, can you get
the link to the...?
Please, don't make me
listen to your music.
I just meant you got
a lot of people with you.
You think they're for you?
Do not worry.
I can do a deal with you all by
myself, thank you very much.
Six more. It's a set up.
You got the diamonds?
I think that's enough.
-We need to move on Klaue.
-Stand down.
We can't afford a shootout.
Vibranium?
Well, I was going to buy a
fancy suitcase, but I...
thought I'd save
myself some money.
It's now or never.
Don't!
Hey!
I've been made.
Wakandans! They're here!
-Get out of here!
-Kill them all!
Diamonds, quick!
Assassin!
You know,
you look just like your old man.
I made it rain!
Let's get out of here, boss!
That was awesome!
It was awesome!
Let's go! Go, go, go, come on!
-Do we just leave him?
-He'll catch up.
Shuri!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Remote driving system activated.
Wait! Which side
of the road is it?
For Bast's sake, just drive!
Okay, calm down.
Whoo! Let's go!
Put some music on. What do
you think this is, a funeral?
What one is he in now?
Hey, split up!
-They're trying to lose us.
-I'll take the right.
We'll take the other two.
I see a shortcut.
I'm not going to make it!
Keep going!
Oh! Brother!
Hey, what was that?
Don't worry about it.
You're doing great.
Guns.
So primitive.
It's a vibranium car, you idiots!
The bullets won't penetrate!
What are you doing?
Just drive.
Jeesh!
Whoo!
Oh, shit!
♪ Opps on the radar ♪
Hey, look at your suit.
You've been taking bullets,
charging it up with kinetic energy.
Pull around the truck.
Where'd he go?
You show off!
There he is!
Hold tight!
All right, let's have some fun.
Hop in.
Put that spear in the trunk.
Faster, Shuri.
I'm going as fast as I can!
Take a right! Take a right!
No, no, no, no, no!
Brother!
Klaue!
Did you think we would forget?
Look at me, murderer!
Where did you get this weapon?
Your savages didn't deserve it.
Oh, mercy, King! Mercy!
Every breath you take
is mercy from me.
King!
The world is watching.
Come on, guys. Let's go, huh?
Yeah.
Hello!
I can see you! I can.
I can see you.
So, this a big mess, huh?
I figured we could go
good cop, bad cop.
I'll talk to him first,
then you guys go in...
We cannot talk to Klaue alone.
I prefer to talk to Klaue alone for
5 minutes to make a fuss here.
After your questioning, we will
take him back to Wakanda with us.
What? No. Look, I like you a lot.
But he's in my custody now.
He's not going anywhere.
Listen, I'm doing you guys a favor
by letting you even be in here.
If touch you again,
I'll stick it to your desktop.
Does she speak English?
When she wants to.
Huh.
I'm going in. And when I'm
done, you guys are up
-Agent Ross.
-Yeah?
I do appreciate your help
in Busan.
You see that.
It's called diplomacy.
You're welcome.
-Okoye.
-Ah.
Play nice.
Americans.
♪ Don't hurt me ♪
♪ No more ♪
♪ What is love? ♪
♪ Baby, don't hurt me ♪
Don't hurt me.
No more.
You know, you really shouldn't
trust the Wakandans.
I'm much more your speed.
I don't trust anybody,
not in this work.
But I am interested in is
that arm cannon out there.
Where'd you get that?
It's an old mining tool that
I made some adjustments to.
But I can, uh, get you one if you like.
Why don't you give me the name
of your supplier and I'll ask them?
He's right outside.
Why don't you ask him yourself?
What? T'Challa?
You're telling me that weapon
on your arm is from Wakanda?
Bingo.
What do you actually know
about Wakanda?
Um...
Shepherds, textiles, cool outfits.
It's all a front.
Explorers searched for it
for centuries.
El Dorado, the Golden City.
They thought they could
find it in South America,
but it was in
Africa the whole time.
A technological marvel.
All because it was built
on a mound of the most
valuable metal known to man.
Isipho, they called it. The gift.
Vibranium.
Vibranium, yeah, strongest
metal on Earth.
It's not just a metal.
They sew it into their clothes.
It powers their city, their tech...
their weapons.
Weapons?
Yeah. Makes my arm cannon
look like a leaf blower.
That's a nice fairy tale, but
Wakanda is a third world country
and you stole all
their vibranium.
I stole...?
All of it?
I took a tiny piece of it.
They have a mountain full of it.
They've been mining it for
thousands of years...
and they still haven't
scratched the surface.
I'm the only outsider
who's seen it
and got out of there alive.
If you don't believe me,
you ask
your friend what his
suit is made of.
What his claws are made of.
Your father told the UN
that Klaue stole all
vibranium you had.
But now, he telling
me you have more?
And do you believe the word of an
arms dealer strapped to a chair?
Where is this?
Behind.
How much more are you hiding?
Something is happening here behind.
Get down!
Whoo!
Cover!
I see you took your
time, didn't you?
Nakia.
He just jumped in front of me.
I don't think he'll make it here.
It hit his spine.
Give me a Kimoyo bead.
This will stabilize him for now.
Give him to us.
We can save him.
Our mission was
to bring back Klaue.
We failed.
This man is a foreign
intelligence operative.
How do we justify bringing
him into our borders?
He took a bullet for me.
That was his choice.
So now we are just
supposed to let him die?
Let us consider that we heal him.
It is his duty to report
back to his country.
And as king, it is your
duty to protect ours.
I am well aware of
my duties, General.
I cannot just let him die...
knowing we can save him.
Where exactly are we taking him?
Great! Another broken
white boy for us to fix.
It's going to be fun.
He will live.
W'Kabi is here.
What's going on brother, huh?
Where is Klaue?
He's not here.
He slipped through our hands.
"Slipped"?
For 30 years your father was
in power and did nothing.
With you, I thought
it would be different.
But it's more of the same.
Let's get going, boss.
Do you always sell to the CIA?
I sell to the highest bidder.
But don't you worry. When
I get back to Joburg,
and I lay low for a bit,
I'll make sure both
of you guys get paid.
I'm not even worried
about the money, bro.
I know you're good for it.
On our way back, just
drop us off in Wakanda.
-You don't want to go there, boy.
-Yeah, I do.
Drop it!
Or your little Bonnie and
Clyde routine ends today.
Put your gun down now!
I'm sorry.
-I'm sorry, Erik.
-It's gon' be okay.
You...
You really want
to go to Wakanda?
They're savages.
This is what they do
to people like us.
I ain't worried about no brandin'.
Check these out.
Each one is for a kill.
You can scar yourself
as much as you like.
To them, you'll just
be an outsider.
You're crazy to think that
you could walk in there.
Ah, to think I saw you
as some crazy American.
Leave us!
So your mission
did not go as planned.
What happened
to my uncle N'Jobu?
My father told me
he disappeared.
There was a man today...
wearing a ring
identical to this one.
That is not possible.
He helped Klaue escape from us
and he was wearing this ring!
My grandfather's ring!
Do not tell me what is possible.
Tell me the truth!
Some truths...
are too much to bear, T'Challa.
That is not your choice to make.
What happened to him?
I promised the King
to say nothing.
I am your king now!
Your uncle took...
a war dog assignment in America.
Your father...
placed me there...
to observe.
Unbeknownst to him,
your uncle fell in love
with an American woman.
They had a child.
The hardships he saw there...
radicalized your uncle.
I observed for
as long as I could.
Their leaders have
been assassinated.
Communities flooded
with drugs and weapons.
They are overly policed
and incarcerated.
All over the planet,
our people suffer
because they don't have
the tools to fight back.
With vibranium weapons, they
could overthrow every country
and Wakanda could rule them all
the right way.
He knew your father
would not support this.
So your uncle betrayed us.
No.
He helped Klaue steal
the vibranium.
No, no, no, no.
You will return home at once
where you will face the Council
and inform them or your crimes.
He drew his weapon on me.
No!
Your father killed
his own brother...
to save my life.
Speak nothing of this.
And the child?
We left him.
We had to...
maintain...
the lie.
What is this?
Just a little gift.
Who you are?
All right, where am I?
Don't scare me like
that, colonizer!
Col--what? My name is Everett.
Yes, I know.
Everett Ross, former Air Force
pilot and now CIA.
Right.
Okay, is this Wakanda?
No, it's Kansas.
How long ago was Korea?
Yesterday.
I don't think so.
Bullet wounds don't just
magically heal overnight.
They do here.
But not by magic, by technology.
Don't touch anything.
My brother will return soon.
These train things...
that's magnetic levitation, right?
Obviously.
Obviously, but I-I never
seen it this...efficient.
The light panels, what are they?
-Sonic stabilizers.
-Sonic what?
In its raw form,
vibranium is too dangerous
to be transported at that speed
so I... I developed a way to
temporarily deactivate it.
There's vibranium
on those trains?
There's vibranium all around us.
That's how I healed you.
Where is T'Challa?
His Kimoyo beads
have been switched off.
Well, we are not joined
at the hip, Okoye.
A man showed up at the border
who claims to have killed Klaue.
What?
W'Kabi is transporting him,
as we speak, to the palace.
We need to find your brother.
An outsider?
No, a Wakandan.
He's not a Wakandan.
He's one of ours.
He killed his own brother...
and left a child behind...
with nothing.
What kind of king...?
What kind of man does that?
No man is perfect.
Not even your father.
He didn't even give him
a proper burial.
My uncle N'Jobu betrayed us,
but my father...
He may have created
something even worse.
Hey.
Look at me.
You can't let your father's
mistakes define who you are.
You get to decide what kind
of king you are going to be.
Brother, you need
to get here now!
Erik Stevens.
Graduated Annapolis, age 19
MIT for grad school.
Joined the SEALs and went
straight to Afghanistan
where he racked up confirmed
kills like it was a video game.
Started calling him Killmonger.
He joined JSOC ghost unit.
Now, these guys are serious.
They will drop off the grid
so they can commit assassinations
and take down governments.
Did he reveal anything
about his identity?
He has a war dog tattoo,
but we have no record of him.
Is this man Wakandan or not?
Tell us what happens.
Speak.
I'm staying in your house.
Serving justice to a man
who stole your vibranium
and murdered your people.
Justice your king couldn't deliver.
I don't care
that you brought Klaue.
Only reason I don't kill
you where you stand
is because I know who you are.
Now what do you want?
I want the throne.
Incredible.
Ya'll sittin' up here comfortable.
Must feel good.
There's about two billion
people all over the world
that looks like us.
But their lives
are a lot harder.
Wakanda has the tools
to liberate them all.
And what tools are those?
Vibranium.
Your weapons.
Our weapons will not be used
to wage war on the world.
It is not our way to be
judge, jury and executioner
for people who are not our own.
Not you own?
But didn't life start right here
on this continent?
So ain't all people your people?
I am not king of all people.
I am King of Wakanda.
And it is my responsibility
to make sure
our people are safe
and that the vibranium
does not fall into the hands
of a person like you.
-Hmm.
-Son.
We have entertained this
charlatan for too long.
Reject his request.
Oh, I ain't requestin' nothin'.
-Ask who I am
-You are Erik Stevens.
An American black operative.
A mercenary nicknamed Killmonger.
That's who you are.
That's not my name, princess.
Ask me, King.
No.
Ask me.
Take him away.
Who are you?
I am N'Jadaka.
Son of Prince N'Jobu.
Son of N'Jobu?
I found my daddy with
panther claws in his chest!
You ain't the son of a king.
You're the son of a murderer.
You're lying!
-Lies!
-I'm afraid not, Queen Mother.
What?
The descendant of N'Jobu.
Hey, Auntie.
I'm exercising my blood right.
To challenge for the
mantles of king!
And Black Panther.
Do not do this, T'Challa.
As the son of Prince N'Jobu,
he is within his rights.
He has no rights here!
The challenge will
take weeks to prepare.
Weeks? I don't need weeks.
The whole country ain't gotta
be there. I just need him.
And somebody to get me
out of these chains.
T'Challa, what do
you know of this?
I accept your challenge.
He'll never beat T'Challa.
He should have just come
to the first challenge
and gotten it over with.
The King will now have the
strength of the Black Panther
stripped away.
Where is Agent Ross?
I locked him in the office.
He's not going anywhere.
This is your last chance.
Throw down your weapons,
and we can handle
this another way.
I lived my entire life
waiting for this moment.
I trained, I lied, I killed
just to get here.
I killed in America, Afghanistan,
Iraq.
I took life
from my own brothers and sisters
right here on this continent.
And all this death...
just so I could kill you.
Let the challenge begin.
Yield!
Snap out of it, T'Challa!
Come on, get up.
Come here.
This is for my father.
Erik!
-Zuri, no.
-Stop!
-Zuri!
-Zuri, don't!
I am the cause
of your father's death.
Not him.
Take me.
I'll take you both, Uncle James.
No!
No! No!
Zuri, no!
No!
No! No!
Zuri! Zuri!
Is this your king? Huh?
Is this your king?
The Black Panther, who's about
to lead you into the future!
Come on, brother!
Is there nothing that can be done?
Him?
He's supposed to protect you?
-No!
No!
No. I'm your king.
-No!
-We have to go now!
Queen Mother, let's go!
The Queen Mother and
Shuri, they are safe?
Yes.
Thank you.
We should get to them immediately.
I cannot.
What?
Go, my heart is with you.
We cannot turn over our nation
to a man who showed up
here only hours ago.
He is of royal blood.
-He killed T'Challa!
-In ritual combat.
Does that really matter?
You are the greatest
warrior Wakanda has.
Help me overthrow him
before he becomes too strong.
Overthrow?
Nakia!
I'm not a spy who can
come and go as they so choose.
I am loyal to that throne,
no matter who sits upon it.
What are you loyal to?
I loved him.
I love my country, too.
Then you serve your country.
No. I save my country.
What's wrong?
The King is dead.
Come with me, unless
you want to join him.
First Baba.
And now my brother.
Mama, we didn't even
get to bury him.
Shh.
-It's me.
-Nakia.
Who is this man?
He's a friend of T'Challa's.
He saved my life.
Where is Okoye?
Okoye's not coming.
She and the Dora Milaje
will serve the new king.
Wait here.
What has happened
to our Wakanda?
Allow the heart-shaped herb
to give you the powers
of the Black Panther
and take you to Ancestral Plane.
What did I tell you about
going into my things?
Hm?
What did you find?
Your home.
I gave you a key hoping that
you might see it someday.
Yes. The sunsets there are
the most beautiful in the world.
But I fear you still
may not be welcome.
Why?
They will say you are lost.
But I'm right here.
No tears for me?
Everybody dies.
It's just life around here.
Well, look at what I've done.
I should have taken
you back long ago.
Instead, we are both
abandoned here.
Well, maybe your home is
the one that's lost.
That's why they can't find us.
Breathe! Breathe, my King, breathe.
Breathe. Breathe.
The heart-shaped herb did that?
-This is all of it?
-Yes.
So when it comes
time for another king,
we will be ready.
Another king?
Yeah, go ahead and
burn all that.
My King, we cannot do that.
It is our tradition--
When I tell you to do something,
I mean that shit.
Burn it all!
You know, where I'm from,
when black folks started revolutions,
they never had the firepower
or resources to fight
their oppressors.
Where was Wakanda?
Hm?
All of that ends today.
We got spies embedded in
every nation on Earth.
Already in place.
I know how colonizers think.
So we're gonna use their
own strategy against them.
We're gonna send vibranium
weapons out to our war dogs.
They'll arm oppressed
people all over the world.
So they can finally rise up
and kill those in power.
And their children.
And anyone else who
takes their side.
It's time they know
the truth about us!
We're warriors!
The world's gonna start over,
and this time, we're on top.
The sun will never set
on the Wakandan empire.
Wakanda has survived for so long
by fighting when only
absolutely necessary.
Wakanda survived in the
past this way, yes.
But the world is
changing, General.
Elders, it is getting smaller.
The outside world
is catching up.
And soon it will
be the conquerors
or the conquered.
I'd rather be the former.
You heard your orders.
Let's get to it.
So, where are we going again?
We are taking the heart-shaped
herb to Jabari land.
Heart-shaped herb? What is that?
It gives whoever takes it
heightened abilities.
It's what made T'Challa so strong.
Nakia.
I don't like this.
The herb belongs to us.
We may be creating a bigger
monster with M'Baku.
Nakia,
you should take it yourself.
I am a spy with no army.
I wouldn't stand a chance.
We'll go.
Oh, boy.
Shh.
Oh, shit.
Look down. Stay calm.
Shuri.
Look down.
Hi.
My son...
was murdered in ritual combat.
-Were the odds fair?
-Yes, but--
So it was less a
murder than a defeat.
Do not rub our noses in it!
Silence!
I make the pronouncements
here, girl.
Look, uh, Your Highness,
the new king is...
The new king...
You cannot talk!
One more word and I will
feed you to my children.
I'm kidding. We are vegetarians.
Great Gorilla M'Baku...
This is why we are here.
To offer this to you.
An outsider sits on our throne.
Only you can help us stop him.
Come with me.
Impossible!
Is he breathing?
He's in a coma.
Barely clinging to life.
One of our fishermen found him
at the edge of the river border.
He brought him to me.
Why do you have him in the snow?
It is the only thing keeping him
from joining the ancestors.
We need to get him to my lab.
I can heal him there.
Take him, he'll be
dead in seconds.
Nakia, the herb.
I call upon the ancestors.
I call upon Bast.
I am here with my son, T'Challa.
Heal him.
We must bury him.
Cover him. Cover him!
Okay.
Glory to the ancestors.
Wake up, T'Challa.
Wake up.
My son.
The time has come
for you to come home
and be reunited with me.
Why?
Why didn't you bring
the boy home?
Why, Baba?
He...
He was the truth I chose to omit.
You were wrong to abandon him.
I chose my people.
I chose Wakanda.
Our future depended
You were wrong!
All of you were wrong!
To turn your backs
on the rest of the world!
We let the fear of discovery
stop us from doing
what is right.
No more!
I cannot stay here with you.
I cannot rest
while he sits on the throne.
He is a monster
of our own making.
I must take the mantle back.
I must!
I must right these wrongs.
Do you have a blanket?
Killmonger has the full
support of our military.
And...
He burned the garden
of the heart-shaped herb.
Of course he did. That's
what he was trained to do.
His unit used to work with the CIA
to destabilize foreign countries.
They would always strike
at transitions of power,
like an election year,
or a death of a monarch.
He got control of
government, the military...
-Our resources.
-Right.
The Great Mound.
Our vibranium, all of my designs.
He will send our weapons
all over the world.
You must get them
out of Wakanda safely.
-What?
-What about you?
The challenge
will have to continue.
T'Challa, we will
not leave Wakanda.
It is my duty to keep you safe.
If he gets control
of our technology,
nowhere will be safe.
The Black Panther lives.
And when fights for
the fate of Wakanda,
I will be right there beside him.
As will I.
I'm in too.
What? You're gonna need
all the help you can get.
Are you're done?
A-Are you-are you-
are you done?
Could you give me and
Lord M'Baku a moment?
Thank you.
I owed you a great debt.
A life for a life.
Consider it paid.
Please allow my mother
to stay here.
No harm will come to her.
I give you my word.
You know, I could use
an army as well.
I bet you could.
But no.
I will give no Jabari
lives towards your cause.
It is our cause.
-It's for all of us.
-Us?
Us? You are the first king to
come here in centuries, and now
you speak of "us"?
I cannot speak for past kings.
But an enemy sits on
the throne right now.
We both know
the power of vibranium.
If Killmonger
gains control of it,
who do you think
he will come for next?
We will not help you.
Everything is on schedule.
Have the spies been alerted?
Yes. Some resistance
to our new mission.
But the war dogs in London,
New York and Hong Kong
are standing by.
We'll strike there first.
The others will come around.
Look at this.
A handheld sonic cannon
powerful enough to stop a tank.
Untraceable by metal detectors.
And we got thousands of 'em.
The world's gonna find out
exactly who we are.
He lives!
N'Jadaka!
What's up?
I never yielded!
And as you can see,
I am not dead!
All that challenge
shit is over with.
I'm the king now.
Get those planes in the air!
Carry out the mission!
-Shuri now.
-Copy that.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Come on, Ross.
W'Kabi, man, kill this clown.
W'Kabi, the challenge
is not complete.
What will we do?
Border Tribe!
You!
Your heart is so full of hatred.
You are not fit to be a king!
Come on.
Ayo, the King!
Come on!
Shields!
W'Kabi, stop this!
Stop this now!
No!
Nakia and I will get control
the Royal Talon with this.
So, what do I do?
You'll have to fly it.
-What?
-You were a great pilot.
Don't worry,
I'll guide you through it.
It's just like riding a hoverbike.
What? You guys have hoverbikes?
Hey, Nakia, take that.
-I'm not a Dora.
-Just put it on, it's armor!
Come!
Good luck, Agent Ross!
-Yeah, I don't know what I'm doing
-We're counting on you.
with this.
Wakanda forever.
Come on!
Go! Go!
Remote piloting system activated.
Oh, my God.
I made it American style for you.
Get in.
All right.
Yes!
Go!
We can't let those weapons
get beyond Wakanda.
All right, I'm on it.
Shut!
Down!
Take the necklace!
Wakanda forever!
Okay, Shuri. I got 'em.
What do I do?
Shoot them down, genius!
Oh, right.
Here goes nothin'.
All right, got 'em.
Oh, shit.
Shit!
Shuri!
What's up, princess?
You will never be a true king.
Brother!
Shuri.
Turn on the train
on the bottom track.
Stabilizers will
deactivate your suit!
You won't have protection!
Neither will he.
Okay!
I don't need a suit to kill you.
Your reign is over!
You sat up here,
safe and protected.
You want to see us become just
like the people you hate so much.
Divide and conquer
the land it takes.
No, I've learned from my enemies.
-Beat 'em at their own game.
-You have become them!
You will destroy the world,
Wakanda included!
The world took
everything away from me!
Everything I ever loved!
But I'ma make sure we're even.
I'ma track down anyone who would
even think of being loyal to you!
And I'ma put their ass in the dirt,
right next to Zuri!
Nakia!
-Are you all right?
-I'm okay, you?
Yes.
Let's go.
Shuri, I've lost one of them,
but two are on my tail.
What the hell was that?
The lab is under attack.
What? Where?
Deactivating hologram.
Ross, you have to get
out of there now!
How long have I got?
Glass integrity is at 50 percent.
Put me back in.
Ross!
Surrender now!
You have three seconds
to lay down their weapons!
One!
Two!
Thr--
Witness the might of the Jabari
firsthand!
Glass integrity is at 15 percent.
-Critical weapons failure.
-Shit!
Shuri, the last cargo ship
is almost at the border,
but they got me trapped
with some kind of cables.
Make an X with your arms!
Sonic overload initiated.
Now, break it.
System rebooting in five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One.
System rebooted.
Yes! We did it!
Great! Now get out of there!
Attack!
Drop your weapon.
Would you kill me, my love?
For Wakanda?
Without question.
This is it for you, cousin.
Hell of a move.
Hell, pops said Wakanda was the
most beautiful he ever seen.
He promised he was gonna
show it to me one day.
Can you believe that?
Kid from Oakland running around
believing in fairy tales.
It's beautiful.
Maybe we can still heal you.
Why?
So you can just lock me up?
Nah.
Just bury me in the ocean...
with my ancestors that
jumped from the ships.
'Cause they knew death
was better than bondage.
Thank you.
You saved me.
You saved my family.
Our nation.
There is nothing to thank me for.
It is our duty to...
It was my duty to fight
for what I love.
I should have...
You can't blame me, I almost died.
Stay.
I think I know a way you can
still fulfill your calling.
Please stay.
Ooh, don't lose it!
Bucket!
Easy.
When you said you would take me
to California for the first time,
I thought you meant Coachella
or Disneyland.
Why here?
This is where our father
killed our uncle.
They're tearing it down.
Good.
They are not tearing it down.
I bought this building.
And that building.
And that one over there.
This will be the first Wakanda
International Outreach Center.
Nakia will oversee
the social outreach.
And you will spearhead the Science
and Information Exchange.
-You're kidding.
-Yeah?
-Oh!
-Oh, my God!
Man, what the hell is that?
It's like a Bugatti spaceship!
It came out of nowhere.
Did y'all see that?
What?
Check this out, bro.
Take this back to the house, yo.
Pull up to school in this.
Hey, look, we can break it apart,
we can sell it.
-On eBay.
-I could get a million a piece.
Ah, I wouldn't do that,
if I were you guys.
-Where you come from?
-From Wakanda.
What is a Wakanda?
Hey, yo!
This yours?
Who...
Who are you?
♪ This may be the night that
my dreams might let me know ♪
♪ All the stars are closer ♪
United Nations, Vienna, Austria
My name is King T'Challa.
Son of King T'Chaka.
I am the sovereign ruler
of the Nation of Wakanda.
And for the first
time in our history,
we will be sharing our
knowledge and resources
with the outside world.
Wakanda will no longer
watch from the shadows.
We cannot.
We must not.
We will work to be an example
of how we as brothers and
sisters on this Earth
should treat each other.
Now more than ever...
the illusions of division
threaten our very existence.
We all know the truth.
More connects us
than separates us.
But in times of crisis.
the wise build bridges
while foolish build barriers.
We must find a way
to look after one another
as if we were one single tribe.
With all due respect,
King T'Challa,
what can a nation of farmers have
to offer the rest of the world?
Subs by enxansix